はい！
デート？
いや、マジ待ったわ！
すみませぇん！
これからデートするわけですし
正しいはずなのに
ひらりひら空回る
[この字幕はNTSubsによって制作されております]
「字幕制作者はonami, danielb]
千葉県民が千葉へ行くといえば
なんだか夢を追ってビッグになりそうな感じがしてしまう
お待たせしました！
ちょっと準備に手間取っちゃいまして・・・
まず間違いなく千葉駅周辺に行くことを指すのだが
この感覚はほかの地域の人には伝わりづらいかもしれない
だからそこは今来たとこって返すべきなんじゃないですかね
たとえば東京都民が東京へ行ってくるって言い出したら
空欄を埋め完成した定理
探しにゆくんだそこへ
The Flowering City
Chiba
未来は歪で
When a Chiba resident says they're going to Chiba Station,
僅かな亀裂から
you would unmistakably assume they were going to the station's east entrance, but...
ikurademo yorete
いくらでも縒れて
This might be difficult to know for people from other prefectures.
理想から逸れてゆくんだ
ぬるま湯がずっと
ぬるま湯がすっと
For example, if someone not from Tokyo
said, "I'm going to Tokyo,"
The Flowering City
Chiba
冷めてゆく音がしてた道を
you get the feeling that they're off to chase their dreams and make it big.
変えるのなら
Sorry!
今なんだ！
こんなレプリカは要らない
Hope you didn't wait, it took some time to get ready.
No, I've seriously been waiting...
本物と呼べるものだけでいい
Didn't I tell you to reply with "Not at all, I just got here myself"?
探しにゆくんだそこへ
We're about to go on a date after all.
でもそれはよくできた
A date?
Yes!
フェアリーテイルみたい
Oh, it's Iroha-chan!
あれっ！イロハちゃんだ！
君は呟いた
Yahallo!
ヤッハロ！
Good afternoon! I'm glad you're still here.
こんにちは！まだいてよかったです！
We were about to go home...
もう帰るところだったのだけれど
Did you have some business with us?
何か用あったのか
Yes! That's right!
はい、そうなんですよ
Senpai, do you have a moment?
先輩、ちょっといいですか
Oh? Yeah...
Then..
じゃ・・・
Um, about the work I requested before...
あの・・・前にお願いした仕事のことなんですけど
Hm? Ah, I got it. I'll do something about it.
あっ・・・やっとくわ。なんとくしとく。
I see. Then is tomorrow at ten in front of Chiba station alright?
そうですか。じゃ明日、十時に千葉駅でいいですか
Eh?! Tomorrow?
えっ、明日！？
No, tomorrow is a bit...
いや、あしたはちょっと
But, there's free time tomorrow!
でも、明日暇じゃないですか
Even if you said that you didn't have free time, I wouldn't know.
じゃないですかって言われても知らないんだけど
I'm talking about you, Senpai.
先輩のことですよ！
Oh, you were talking about me.
俺の話？
No, isn't it weird that you were talking about m–
いや、俺の話になっているのもおかしいでしょう
Then, I'll be counting on you tomorrow too!
じゃ明日もよろしくです
I'll be looking forward to Senpai's plan in action!
先輩の仕事振り、楽しみにしてますんで
A date?
デート？
Yes!
はい！
Isn't Hayama-senpai about to become really busy with things?
ハヤマ先輩、近頃色々大変だったじゃないですか
I thought casually introducing him to some light fun would be good.
なので気晴らしに軽く遊びに誘えたらいいかなと！・・
Huh. Well that's fine.
ほっ・・・いいんじゃないの
Isn't that why Senpai said he'd think of a date course?
それで先輩がデートコース考えてくれるって言ったじゃないですか
Eh? Did someone say that? Who did? Me?
え？！そんなこと言った？誰が？俺が？
Maybe I did.
言ったかもね
So? Where are we going?
で？どこ行く？
You're leaving it to the girl all of a sudden?
いきなり人任せですか
When I act alone I get excited while making intricate plans, but
俺は一人で行動するときはわくわくしながら綿密な計画を立てるが
when there's other people, fundamentally, my style is to follow after them.
誰かいるときは基本あとから付いていくスタイルだ
Jeez, it's fine...
もう、いいです
Let's think about it while walking around.
歩きながら考えましょう
It's cold here too.
ここ寒いですし
I wonder who's the one that made me wait in that cold place?
その寒い所で待ちぼうけ食わせたのはどこのどいつなんですかね
Senpai, what kind of place do you normally go to?
先輩、普段どいうとこ行くんですか
Home.
家・・・
Try again.
やり直し
S-Sure...
Aren't things like movies fine? We can kill two hours for now.
映画とかいいんじゃないの
とりあえず二時間は潰せるぞ
When was it decided we're killing time?
なんで時間潰し前提なんですか
Well, I guess I'll leave it up to you...
まぁ、先輩に任せますけど・・・
Then, the movies it is.
じゃ、映画だな
I want to watch this!
私、これが見たいです！
Then I'll watch this.
じゃ、俺、こっち見るわ
We'll meet back here when we're done.
終わったらここでで待ち合わせな
Eh? What?
えっ？何？
I see...
なるほど・・・
Since you act like that, it ends up that way...
そういう対応するからああなるんですね
Hm?
Bowling, billiards, and ping-pong, huh.
ボーリング、ビリヤードに卓球ね
This doesn't really matter Senpai, but billiards doesn't exactly suit you.
どうでもいいですけど先輩、ビリヤードとか似合わないですね
Leave me alone.
ほっとけ
Ah, but if it's ping-pong, you fit in!
あ、でも卓球なら似合いますよ
I don't need a follow-up like that...
そんなフォロー要らないよ
Let's play ping-pong instead of a movie!
映画はやめて卓球やりませんか
That's okay too, but won't it be hard with those shoes?
それでもいいけどその靴、厳しくねぇか
W-What?
んー何？
No, I just thought you're surprisingly observant.
いいえ 意外とちゃんと見てるんだなと思いまして
I can tell that much even if I'm not being observant because your height is different than it is usually.
普段と目線の高さ違うんだから、それくらい見なくても分かる
Oh, it's true. You're closer than you are normally.
あ、ほんとですね・・・いつもより近いです
Well, you can just borrow shoes.
まあ、靴は借りればいいか
Yup!
はい
Jeez! How sly is this kouhai?
まったく！なんてあざといんだ、この後輩は！
I haven't played ping-pong since classes in middle school!
私、卓球って中学の授業以来です
You can choose it as an option for P.E when you're a second-year.
二年になれば体育の選択でとれるぞ
Then...!
では
It's settled that you'll treat me to lunch if I win?
私が勝ったらお昼奢ってもらうってことでいいですね
Well, that's fine.
ま、いいけどな
Die!
死ね！
Hang on, that shout is weird...
いや、その掛け声、おかしいだろう
Why are you acting so triumphant with such a satisfied smile?
なんで満足気な笑顔で勝ち誇ってるんですかね
Alright, it's my serve.
じゃ、私のサーブですね
Oh! Senpai, please wait a moment!
先輩、ちょっと待ってください
It's bad, it's ba-
やばいですよ・・・
Furyah!
うりゃあああ！
That's naive.
甘いんだよ・・・
Keh! How unfair!
卑怯な！
"What's unfair"?
何が卑怯って！？
The table is completely getting in
the way, I can't see anything!
結局台が邪魔で絶対見えないことなんだよ
The table is completely getting in
the way, I can't see anything!
Let's see, Senpai right now has eight points.
えっと、先輩がいま八ポイントで
My points are one, two, three, four...
私のポイントが一、二、三、四・・・
Senpai, what time is it right now?
先輩、いま何時ですか
Uh, it's about eleven.
ちょうど十一時だろう
Eleven, I see. So, my points are twelve, thirteen, fourteen, fifteen-
「十一」、そうですか
で、私のポイントは十二、十三、十四、十五・・・
Six. Six points.
六だ！六ポイント。
You're too bold with that obvious trick.
その時そば大胆すぎるだろう
It's a no, even if you pout.
むくれてもダメ！
Come on, let's go.
ほれ、行くぞ
Oh! That was out so it's my point, right?
あっ！アウトだったんだよ。私のポイントですね
Why is this girl lying with a straight face?
何でしれっと嘘つくの、その子は？
That was my win, right?
俺の勝ちでいいな？
It can't be helped. I lost this time.
仕方ありません。今回は私の負けでいいです
Then, thanks for lunch.
じゃ昼飯、よろしく
H-Huh? Did I possibly make Irohas cry?
あれっ？もしかしてイロハス泣かせちゃった？
Eh? What? What's wrong?
え、何？どうしたの？
I said you'd treat me if I won,
私が勝ったら奢ってもらうとは言いましたが
but I didn't say I'd treat you if you won, Senpai!
先輩が勝ったら奢るとは言ってません！
Indeed...
っ確かに・・・
Well, I wasn't thinking I'd make you treat me in the first place so it's all good...
まぁ、別に最初から奢ってもらおうとは思ってないからいいんだけどよ
But even so, aren't you being a bit cunning?
それにしたってちょっとずるくないですかね
Isn't it like a girl to be a bit cunning?
ちょっとずるいくらいのほうが女の子らしいじゃないですか
It doesn't concern me, but that logic isn't going to pass by every guy.
どうでもいいけど、その理論。
全部の男子に通じるわけじゃねぇからな
No, no, no.
いやいやいや！
Of course there's no way I would do that around Hayama-senpai!
もちろん、ハヤマ先輩の前とかやるわけないじゃないですか
What would I do if he started to hate me?
嫌われたらどうするんですか
Well... I think Hayama would be happier to see that side of you.
まあ、ハヤマ、そっちのほうが喜ぶと思うけどな
Huh?!
Is that for real?! Where is that information from?
マジですか！？それどこ情報ですか
There is no particular source.
ソースは特にねえよ
It's not credible if there's no source.
情報源も曖昧なんじゃ根拠に欠けますね
It doesn't seem I can act that way yet.
まだ実行に移せそうにないです
There's no need to sweat over it.
別に焦んなくてもいいんじゃないの
For the time being he's...
あいつ当分は・・・
That's why... for now...
だからしばらくは・・・
Hm?
I'll act this way only to you, Senpai.
こんなことするの、先輩にだけですよ
Aren't you a bit hungry?
ちょっとなか空きませんか
Hm? Yeah.
It scores high points if you're well-informed about delicious food!
美味しいご飯に詳しいとポイント高い
Ha... it's ramen?
はっ・・・ラメんですか
No, it's because it's something I always eat.
いや、俺がいつも食ってるものっていうから
Well, it is you, Senpai, after all..
まあ、先輩ですもんね
And it was me that said I'd leave it to you, so I guess it's fine...
任せるといったのは私ですしいいですけど
What is this?
なんですか、これ？
Is that oil? Maybe wax?
油ですか？マジですか？
Let's eat.
いただきます
This is frustrating...
悔しいですけど
...but it tasted good.
美味しかったです
That's a relief.
それはよかった
Well... I guess taking a girl into a shop that's hard to go alone to scores some high points.
まぁ 女の子だけだと入りづらいお店に
連れていてもらえるっていうのは結構ポイント高いかもですね
Don't you want to eat something sweet now?
なんか甘い物食べたくないですか
Hm? Sure.
Hey, hey, seriously?
おいおいマジかよ
This is Chiba, you know. Is it okay for there to be this kind of café?
ここ千葉だぞ！
オサレなカフェあっていいのか
Then, let's g–
じゃ行きま・・・
Bad...!
やっばっ！
What? What is it?
何？何なの？
It's the Vice President and Secretary-chan.
副会長と書記ちゃんです
What? Are those two going out?
何、あの二人付き合ってんの
Who knows? I doubt it.
さあ、違うんじゃないですか
Besides it's a bit simplistic to say things like they're dating from just hanging out–
だいたい遊びに行ったくらいで付き合ってるとかちょっと単じゅ・・・
What was that, were you hitting on me just now?
何ですか。もしかして今私の子と口説いてましたか
There's a limit to shamelessness, already acting like my boyfriend from just hanging out one time!
一回遊びに行ったくらいでもう彼氏面とか図々しいにもほどがあるんで
I'm sorry, but you can only do that after hanging out some more times!
もう何回か重ねてからにしてもらっていいですか。ごめんなさい！
Whatever, let's go inside. Outside is cold.
いいから、入ろうぜ。外寒い
Please wait for me!
ちょっと待ってくだいさい！
Well, that near-miss was honestly unexpected...
まあ、ニアミスしちゃったのは正直予想外でしたけど・・・
Next time let's go someplace where there's less people we know!
今度はもうちょっと知り合いの少ないところにしましょうね
There's a next time?
次があるのか
Why do you seem a bit unpleasant about that?
なんでちょっと嫌そうなんですか
Thank you for waiting!
お待たせしました
Is this everything you ordered?
ご注文の品はお揃いでしょうか
Ah, excuse me!
あっ、すみません！
Can you please take a picture?
カメラお願いしてもいいですか
Sure, I don't mind!
はい、構いませんよ
Hmm?
Ok, Senpai! Make a peace sign! Peace!
はい、先輩、ピースですピース
No. It's not like I have to be in the photo.
いやだよ。別に俺を映んなくてもいいだろう
The ice cream's gonna melt.
アイス溶けちゃうんだけど
It won't melt that fast!
そんなすぐに解けませんよ！
It's fine so hurry up!
いいから、早くです！
It'd be better to get a bit closer.
もう少し寄っていただいたほうが・・・
Okay, here we go.
ではいきますよ
Thank you very much!
ありがとうございます
It did melt a bit after all...
やっぱりちょっと溶けてんじゃねーか
Well, I guess you scored ten points for today.
まあ、今日のところは十点って感じですかね
I'm just gonna ask, out of what?
一応聞くけど、何点満点？
Out of one hundred, of course!
もち百ですよ
Why that low?
なんでそんなに低いんだよ
Firstly, minus ten points because you weren't Hayama-senpai.
まずハヤマ先輩じゃなかったのがマイナス十点。
This was an impossible challenge from the very start...
最初から無理難題なんだよな
Then, minus fourty points if we include your conduct.
それこら言動もろもろ含めてマイナス四十点ですよ
That's, well... fair, I guess.
それはまあ、妥当だな・・・
So you were somewhat aware of it yourself...
一応、自覚はあったんですね
It's minus fifty points for the part where you easily accepted a girl's invitation.
女の子に呼ばれてホイホイついてきちゃうあたり、マイナス五十点
Ow.
You're the one that called me out.
お前が呼んだんだろうが
Plus, that's zero points.
ってゆうかゼロになっちゃたしさ
But, I'll give you a bonus ten points because it was fun!
でも楽しかったのでおまけで十点あげます！
Thanks for that.
それ、どうもう
How was it for you, Senpai...?
先輩はどうでした
Well, it was along those lines for me too.
まあ、俺はそんな感じだな
It was a bit tiring though.
ちょっと疲れたけど・・・
"Bit tiring"? Aren't you being a bit too frank?
疲れたとか正直過ぎませんかね！？
That's fine though.
もういいですけど
It just means you were putting in that much effort as my partner!
それだけちゃんと私の相手をしたってことですし
What is with that super annoyed face?!
何ですか、その超面倒くさそうな顔！？
There isn't a girl that isn't annoying.
面倒くさくない女の子なんていませんよ
That's true. There aren't any people who aren't annoying in the first place.
そうだろうな
面倒くさくない人間なんてそもそもいないし
Uwah, Senpai, you're annoying!
うっわ、先輩面倒くさっ
This girl is cruel!
ひでーな、こいつ
Today was a good enough reference, for now!
とりあえず、今日は参考になりました
Thank you.
ありがとうございます
Y...Yeah...
Senpai, make sure you properly reference from this as well!
先輩もちゃんと参考にしてくだいね
Ah... Well, what?
まあ、何・・・
Thanks for today.
今日はサンキュー
Then, I'll see you again at school.
それじゃまた学校で・・・
Be careful on your way back.
気を付けて帰れよ
Girls are made of sugar and spice, and something nice.
女の子はお砂糖とスパイスと素敵な何かでできている
I think that was from Mother Goose.
「マザー･グース」だったか
Though, I get the feeling Isshiki has a bit too much spice in her.
最も、イッシキは少しばかりスパイスを利かせすぎな気がするが
No matter how much sugar you mix in,
habañeros are still habañeros.
どんなに砂糖を塗してもハバネロはハバネロだ
It won't be complete without something nice.
素敵な何かがないと成立しない
Good work everyone!
お疲れ様です！
Oh, Iroha-chan! Yahallo!
お、イロハちゃん！ヤッハロ！
Ah! Senpai, thank you for your time the other day!
この間はどうもうでした
Yeah...
So, I was thinking...
で、私ちょっと思ったんですけど・・・
How about making a free newspaper by the Student Council!
生徒会でフリーペーパーを作ろうかなと！
What?
はい？
Free newspaper is like, that, right?
フリーペーパーってなんかあれでしょう
Yes! It's exactly that!
はい。そのあれです
That's fine, right? Though I don't know what you're going to make it about.
いいんじゃねーの？どんなん作るかは知らんけど
I've sort of already decided on that.
それについては一応もう決めてあるんですよ
Things like places to hang out, restaurants with good food, and cute cafés.
遊べる場所とかおいしいごはん屋さんとか・・・かわいカフェーとか
Ehh... I want to see that!
見たい、見たい！
I don't really have any interest, so I don't have to see–
私、別に興味はないから見なくてもっ
Ah! How cute!
あっ！かわいい！
It's great, isn't it?
いいですよね！
Can you show me that photo just now again?
ちょっと今の写真もう一度見せてもらえるかしら
Yes, of course!
はい！いいですよ！
Th-Those cat sundries...
その猫の・・・
This is great too!
これもいいね！
This is super cute also!
これ、超かわいいですよ
Can you print this out in the reference room afterwards?
What's next, what's next?
あと、あとは？
Eh? What?
ん？何？
Ah... Yeah...
No, kinda... I-I just thought I'd like to try going there too...
いや・・・なんか、私も行ってみたいなと思って・・・
It seems like a very fun photo, yes?
ずいぶん楽しそうな写真ね？
U-Um... I had Senpai cooperate with me for the coverage...
えと、先輩に収財に協力してもらったんですけど・・・
Ah, that's right!
そう！
Actually, all the pages haven't been filled yet so I was having trouble!
実はですね・・・まだページ埋まらなくて困ってて・・・
So...
それで・・・
Um... Then-
えと、それじゃ・・・
You'll do the coverage?
取材行ってくれるんですか！？
That's a life saver!
助かります！
Ah, this is the Student Council's property so feel free to use it!
生徒会の備品なのでぜひぜひ使ってください
Yukinon...
ユキノン・・・
If it's on the weekend, I'm free.
週末なら開いているわ
I got it...
分かったよ
The Flowering City
Chiba
What kind of company slave am I to go out on rest days two weeks in-a-row?
二週続けて休日勤務とは。どの社畜ですか、おれは！？
Oh, you're early.
お、早いな
It's normal conduct in society to arrive five minutes early.
五分前集合は社会行動の基本よ
Is that so?
そうですか
Hikki! Yukinon!
ヒッキ！ユキノン！
Yahallo!
ヤっハロ！
So, where are we going?
でどこ回るんだ？
Yukinon, cute clothes like this definitely suit you!
ユキノン！こういうかわいい系も絶対似合うよ！
D-Do they?
そっ、そうかしら
And, things like this too!
あと、こういうのも！
That's definitely a bit...
それはさすがに
Ehh? It's fine, isn't it? It is! It really is! Try it on once!
えっ！？いいじゃん！いいモン、すごく一回着てみよ!
Ah... Ah, no...
Not good, not good.
いかんいかん
Once you see shops like that, you just get interested.
ああいうお店が目に入るとつい気になってしまうが
There's nothing happy to see in the clubroom after all, yeah.
不躾に見るのはよろしくないな
But, you just end up looking. I'm a boy after all!
だけど「つい見ちゃ 男の子だもん」
You'll get reported if you conduct such suspicious activity.
あまり不審な行動を取ってると通報されるわよ
I won't get reported from this level.
この程度で通報はされん
At most, this is the level the shop assistant comes close and says something to me.
せいぜい店員さんが近寄って声かけてくるくらいだ
That's already something you should try to avoid.
それは十分に恥ずべきこどでしょう
I wish you wouldn't behave too
embarrassingly since you're with us.
一緒に来ているのだからあまり恥ずかしい真似はしないでほしいわね
Yeah. I'll be careful.
あ、気をつけろ
Where's Yuigahama?
ユイガハマは？
She's checking if we can publish the store for the free newspaper.
フリーペーパーに掲載できるか確認中
Volume UP Bra
Just by sleeping while wearing this, you'll go
I wonder if Yuigahama-san's
negotiations have gone well...
ユイガハマさん上手く交渉を出来ているかしら
Volume UP Bra
Just by sleeping while wearing this, you'll go
It's okay! You have hope left!
大丈夫。希望は残ているよ
If you think genetically anyway.
遺伝的に考えればね
Nope.
いやあ・・・
I know she loves cats like cats love Friskies,
猫大好きフリスキなのは分かるけど
but I wish she'd pay a little more attention to her surroundings...
もう少し周りのこと気にしてほしいな
Look at this!
見て見て
Hikki! Isn't this dog cute?
ヒッキ、この子可愛くない？
A miniature dachshund?
ミニチュアダックス
That's the same breed you're already raising.
そりゃお前んちで飼ってるやつだろう
Yup! I was wondering how she'd be as Sable's wife?
サーベルさんの嫁さんにどうかなって
Here!
はい！
Y-Yeah...
I wonder if it's like this...?
こういう感じなのかな
What is?
何が？
I-It's nothing!
なんでもない
Oh, that's what...
あ、そういう・・・
And then, it had been a while and we got on the monorail,
んでね久々にモノレールに乗ったんだけど
but we got lost on the way back home.
帰り道迷っちゃって
Isn't a part of Chiba station in the middle of construction?
あのさ、千葉駅って工事中じゃん！
That's right.
そうね
Both the right and left became the East exit!
右も左も東口だそう！
These are good!
いいじゃないですか
All of them are okay!
どれだかオーケーです
Really? That's a relief!
そっか。よかったよ！
Indeed!
はい！
I'm glad it seems to have become a proper reference.
ちゃんと参考になったみたいでよかったです
Ah, that's right!
あっ、そうだ！
It's a bit off to say "while we're at it",
ついでと言っては何ですけど、
but how about one photo of
everyone in the Service Club?
奉仕部のみなさんで一枚どうですか
Ah, that's a good idea! Let's take one together too, Iroha-chan!
いいね！イロハちゃんも一緒に撮ろうよ！
Yes! Let's afterwards!
はい！のちほどぜひぜひ
So, first let's take a photo of the Service Club!
なのでまずは奉仕部のみなさんで
Yes, yes! That looks good!
そうそういい感じです！
Hey.
ちょっと
Isn't this arrangement kind of weird?
この構図なんかおかしくない
Note: Shichi-Go-San is a traditional rite of passage and a festival day in Japan held for 3 and 7 years old girls and 3 and 5 years old boys celebrate their growth and well-being.
Doesn't this look like Shichi-Go-San?
七五三みたいじゃないですか
Hikigaya-kun, you're being stubborn.
ヒキガヤくん、往生際が悪いわよ
Iroha-chan! It's all good!
イロハちゃん、いいよ！
Then I'm going to take it.
では、 いきますよ！
Okay, cheese!
はい！チーズー！
Here, Senpai.
はい！先輩！
It's a good photo.
いい写真ですよ
Indeed, it's not as bad as I thought.
確かに思ったよりは悪くないな
I still don't know how to define or describe this club.
依然として呼び方も定義も分かりはしない、
But, if I put it in words, I felt that our feelings...
言葉にすれば食い違ってしまう思いが
were drawn in this photo.
描かれている気がした
That's why it's not as bad as I thought.
だから思ったよりは悪くない
Surely, girls are made of
sugar and spice, and something nice.
制服も教科書もそう
勝手に変えられるわけじゃない
楽しくてちょっと空虚
時間のなか泳ぎ続ける
平静さを装うためだけ
振舞い方の計算式
解いてばかり
これは恋だとしたなら
孤独という強さを失くしそうで
壊れやすいのeveryday world
はみだす気持ち
臆病なまま
誰もみな傷ついてく